Manhattan Woolen Records 6762
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Manhattan Woolen Records
1903-1932
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Manhattan Woolen
6762
0.75 cubic feet
0.5 linear ft.
Correspondence, records (documents).
Records include certificate of incorporation, amendments and bylaws, 1903-1924; minutes of directors' meetings, 1916-1933; minutes of stockholders' meetings, 1924-1932; correspondence, 1915-1930; record of stock purchases and transfers, 1906-1932; and stock certificates and stubs, 1903-1932.
11021723
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
M. Clark, September 05, 2019
EAD encoding:
Marcie Farwell, October 09, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Located in New York City and incorporated in 1903 the company acted as a selling agent for the American Woolen Co., which was headquartered in New York City with mills throughout New England. Company liquidated in 1933.
Scope and Contents
Includes stock ledger of shareholders, 1903-1932; stock transfer record, 1906-1932; certificate of incorporation, amendments, bylaws, 1903-24; minutes of directors' meetings, 1916-1933; minutes of stockholders' and directors' meetings, 1924-1933; and loose stock certificates & stubs, 1903-1932.
Custodial History
American Textile History Museum Collection, gift of Joseph Knight.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Articles of incorporation; Business records; Manufacturers' agents; Minutes (administrative records); Stock certificates; Textile industry; Woolen and worsted manufacture; Woolen goods industry; Selling agents.; Wool technology -- General; American Woolen Company.; Manhattan Woolen Company.
11021723
- Certificate of Incorporation & Amendment (Dec. 16, 1903-Mar. 17, 1924), 1903-1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- By-Laws and Amendments (Feb. 2, 1909-Aug. 8, 1922), 1909-1922 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Directors meetings - Manhattan Woolen Company - 1916 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Directors meetings - Manhattan Woolen Company - 1916 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Directors meetings - Manhattan Woolen Company - 1916 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Directors & Stockholders - meetings minutes 1924-1926 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Minutes of Directors & Stockholders meetings 1927-1929 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Directors & Stockholders meeting minutes 1930-32, 1930-1932 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Certificate of Election of Directors Dec. 18, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence - re: stocks & Treasurer's correspondence -- Manhattan Woolen Company 1915-1922 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence - Treasurer's Correspondence - re: Stocks, Money matters - Manhattan Woolen Company 1923-1930 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Stock Certificate Stubs 1903-1932 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Stock Certificates 1903-1907 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Stock Certificates 1915-1921 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Stock Certificates 1922-1931 (Box 1, Folder 15)